<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
 <title>USPTO Other Events</title>
<link>https://guides.lib.ucr.edu/c.php?g=932732</link>
 <description>This feed provides easy access to USPTO Other events.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
 <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 09:24:35 PST</lastBuildDate>
<webManager>katherine.koziar@ucr.edu</webManager>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-3</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-3</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on February 14, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part V: Understanding the role of claims in a patent application</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-v-understanding-role-claims-patent-application-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-v-understanding-role-claims-patent-application-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you an inventor preparing to file a patent application? In part five of this eight-part recurring series, United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) experts will discuss the parts of the claim, show examples of claim illustrations from issued U.S. patents, and help participants develop a better appreciation of how a patent examiner views a claim. To get the most out of this workshop, you should have an intermediate knowledge of the intellectual property (IP) system and of patents, specifically. We recommend that you complete the previous sessions in the series, Part I: IP basics and Part IV: Learn how to draft your patent application, before attending. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademarks for librarians</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademarks-librarians-0</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademarks-librarians-0</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a librarian looking for a better understanding of trademark concepts? Do you want to be able to share reliable resources with businesses looking to protect their intellectual property? The United States Patent and Trademark Office's Patent and Trademark Resource Center Program is offering a new webinar that introduces trademark concepts and resources for professional librarians and library staff. This webinar will cover: Types of trademarks Trademark application process Benefits of federal registration Common reasons for refusal USPTO resources Patent and Trademark Resource Centers (PTRCs) and how they can help Please register to attend this free virtual webinar, which will be held Tuesday, February 20, from 2-3 p. m. ET. Register today For more information, email PTRCP@uspto.gov. Accessibility</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Women's Entrepreneurship Series &#38;#8212; Leading with purpose: Women making a difference</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/womens-entrepreneurship-series-leading-purpose-women-making-difference</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/womens-entrepreneurship-series-leading-purpose-women-making-difference</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 18:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on February 21, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>2024 Black Innovation and Entrepreneurship program: Innovate, Elevate, and Empower</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/2024-black-innovation-and-entrepreneurship-program-innovate-elevate-empower</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/2024-black-innovation-and-entrepreneurship-program-innovate-elevate-empower</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VI: Learn how to protect your IP abroad</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vi-learn-how-protect-your-ip-abroad-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vi-learn-how-protect-your-ip-abroad-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Did you know that patents offer territorial rights, which means there is no such thing as an international or global patent? Learn how to help protect your intellectual property (IP) in foreign jurisdictions. In part six of this eight-part recurring series, United States Patent and Trademark Office's (USPTO) International Patent Legal Administration experts will discuss considerations and options for filing foreign patent applications. The discussion will include an overview of the Patent Cooperation Treaty (PCT) and the use of the Paris Convention for non-PCT countries. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Foster a culture of creativity in the classroom with invention and intellectual property education</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/foster-culture-creativity-classroom-invention-and-intellectual-property-education</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/foster-culture-creativity-classroom-invention-and-intellectual-property-education</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 18:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>At this month's K-12 education webinar, the United States Patent and Trademark Office's (USPTO) Office of Education invites you to join a teacher professional development session held by USPTO educational engagement contractor STEMis ED, on February 27 from 6-7 p. m. ET. Learn about new tools and strategies educators can use to unlock the full potential of their students through invention and intellectual property (IP) education. Education experts Kathy Hoppe and Christine Lawlor-King, both former educators with more than 30 years of combined experience in the classroom, will lead an engaging and interactive discussion on the SCAMPER method. SCAMPER&#8212;Substitute, Combine, Adapt, Modify, Put to another use, Eliminate, and Reverse&#8212;is an educational framework that draws upon students' creativity to solve problems, guides brainstorming and critical thinking, and encourages the development of new ideas. By the end of this webinar, teachers will have a new, valuable set of tools to use in their classroom, and an understanding of how invention and IP education can be integrated in their curriculum. Visit the event page to learn more and sign up. This is a fantastic professional development opportunity for teachers seeking to deepen their knowledge of invention education and encourage innovation in their students. Register Here This webinar will be presented by: Kathy Hoppe is the owner of STEMis ED and educational engagement contractor with the USPTO's Office of Education. Kathy has over 30 years of experience in the classroom and is a former Albert Einstein Distinguished Educator (2013-15) placed at the National Science Foundation in the Directorate of Engineering. Christine Lawlor-King is an expert consultant in the field of invention education. A former middle school teacher, Christine recently served as Invention Education Program Manager for Lemelson-MIT and is a recipient of the STEM Connector's Community Trailblazer Award. USPTO Professional development webinars The USPTO hosts monthly professional development webinars for K-12 educators interested in integrating IP, innovation, and invention activities into their STEM/STEAM curriculum. Whether you are a school administrator, teacher, student, parent, or caregiver, you are welcome to join us every month to hear from educators and learn about different types of IP, including patents, trademarks, copyrights, and trade secrets. These sessions can help inspire a classroom of problem solvers and shape career choices. Webinars are held on the last Tuesday of each month from 6-7:30 p. m. ET. Visit the USPTO's Office of Education page or email education@uspto.gov to learn more. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on February 28, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VII: How to file a patent application using Patent Center</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vii-how-file-patent-application-using-patent-center-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vii-how-file-patent-application-using-patent-center-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Looking for more information on using Patent Center? In part seven of this eight-part recurring series, United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) experts will teach participants how to use this tool to file and manage patent documents online. This presentation will feature filing application documents in DOCX format, including using Patent Center training mode to practice filing. You will learn about some helpful resources, such as the Inventors Assistance Center (IAC) and the Patent Electronics Business Center (EBC). Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Getting started with Patent Public Search</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/getting-started-patent-public-search-1</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/getting-started-patent-public-search-1</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you puzzled by patent searching or confused by the patent searching options available on the internet? Whether you are a novice searcher or an experienced one, the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) is here to help.  Librarians from the Patent and Trademark Resource Center Program, who are experienced with educating users on USPTO search tools, will show you how to use the new Patent Public Search tool. The virtual webinar will be held on Thursday, February 29, from 2-3 p. m. ET. Register today For more information pertaining to this webinar, please email PTRCP@uspto.gov. Accessibility</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Attend the Public Engagement Partnership meeting</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/attend-public-engagement-partnership-meeting</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/attend-public-engagement-partnership-meeting</guid>
	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-6</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-6</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on March 6, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VIII: Common mistakes and post-filing support</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-viii-common-mistakes-and-post-filing-support-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-viii-common-mistakes-and-post-filing-support-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you an inventor? Join us for this session full of important tips on filing a patent application and what to do after you file for a patent. In the final part of this eight-part recurring series, you will learn about common mistakes to avoid, and you'll gain a better understanding of post-filing procedures and support. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>National Medal of Technology and Innovation Webinar 2024</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/national-medal-technology-and-innovation-webinar-2024</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/national-medal-technology-and-innovation-webinar-2024</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>The National Medal of Technology and Innovation (NMTI) is America's highest honor for technological achievement and innovation. The president of the United States presents the NMTI at a special White House ceremony. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-7</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-7</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on March 13, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-8</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-8</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on March 20, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademarks for librarians</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademarks-librarians</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademarks-librarians</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a librarian looking for a better understanding of trademark concepts? Do you want to be able to share reliable resources with businesses looking to protect their intellectual property? The United States Patent and Trademark Office's Patent and Trademark Resource Center Program is offering a new webinar that introduces trademark concepts and resources for professional librarians and library staff. This webinar will cover: Types of trademarks Trademark application process Benefits of federal registration Common reasons for refusal USPTO resources Patent and Trademark Resource Centers (PTRCs) and how they can help Please register to attend this free virtual webinar, which will be held Wednesday, March 20, from 2-3 p. m. ET. Register today For more information, email PTRCP@uspto.gov. Accessibility</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Getting started with Patent Public Search</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/getting-started-patent-public-search-0</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/getting-started-patent-public-search-0</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you puzzled by patent searching or confused by the patent searching options available on the internet? Whether you are a novice searcher or an experienced one, the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) is here to help.  Librarians from the Patent and Trademark Resource Center Program, who are experienced with educating users on USPTO search tools, will show you how to use the new Patent Public Search tool. The virtual webinar will be held on Thursday, March 21, from 2-3 p. m. ET. Register today For more information pertaining to this webinar, please email PTRCP@uspto.gov. Accessibility</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-2</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-2</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on March 28 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Patent Pro Bono Program: Pathways to Inclusive Innovation</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/patent-pro-bono-program-pathways-inclusive-innovation-1</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/patent-pro-bono-program-pathways-inclusive-innovation-1</guid>
	<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 09:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A fireside chat with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-1</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-1</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Come join us for a laid back and informational fireside chat that will give you an inside look at being a patent examiner at the USPTO. You will get the opportunity to engage in insightful conversations and get answers to your questions directly from team members. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-3</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-3</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on May 15 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A fireside chat with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-2</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-2</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Come join us for a laid back and informational fireside chat that will give you an inside look at being a patent examiner at the USPTO. You will get the opportunity to engage in insightful conversations and get answers to your questions directly from team members. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on July 9 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner. </description>
</item>

 
</channel>
</rss>