<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
 <title>USPTO Trademark Events</title>
<link>https://guides.lib.ucr.edu/c.php?g=932732</link>
 <description>This feed provides easy access to USPTO Trademark events.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
 <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 09:24:35 PST</lastBuildDate>
<webManager>katherine.koziar@ucr.edu</webManager>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 7: Keeping your registration alive</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-7-keeping-your-registration-alive-13</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-7-keeping-your-registration-alive-13</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this seventh module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll focus on what happens after registration, including mandatory filings to keep your registration alive. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early. This module will cover the following topics: Trademark basics Required post-registration filings Optional post-registration filings Examination of post-registration filings Finding help This module will be presented live via Webex from 2-3:30 p. m. ET on Tuesday, February 20, 2024, and will conclude with a question-and-answer session. Please register by February 19. Register today Be sure to check out our other boot camp modules running consecutively every week for the eight-week duration. You can attend the whole series or just the specific modules that best meet your needs. Separate registration is required for each module. After each event, we'll email registrants links to a video recording of the module and a PDF of the presentation materials. You will only receive access to the recording if you are signed up for that module. For questions about the event or the boot camp series, please contact TMWebinar@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 8: Question-and-answer panel</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-8-question-and-answer-panel-12</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-8-question-and-answer-panel-12</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this final module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll provide a unique opportunity for you to 'meet the trademark experts. ' Come prepared with all of your trademark questions to share with our Law Office Managing Attorneys and other trademark experts. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early. This module will be presented live via Webex from 2-3:30 p. m. ET on Tuesday, February 27, 2024. Please register by February 26. Register today Be sure to check out our other boot camp modules running consecutively every week for the eight-week duration. You can attend the whole series or just the specific modules that best meet your needs. Separate registration is required for each module. After each event, we'll email registrants links to a video recording of the module and a PDF of the presentation materials. You will only receive access to the recording if you are signed up for that module. For questions about the event or the boot camp series, please contact TMWebinar@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
</channel>
</rss>