<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
 <title>USPTO Patent Events</title>
<link>https://guides.lib.ucr.edu/c.php?g=932732</link>
 <description>This feed provides easy access to USPTO Patent events.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
 <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 09:01:08 PST</lastBuildDate>
<webManager>katherine.koziar@ucr.edu</webManager>

 
<item> <title>Federal trademark searching: Overview</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/federal-trademark-searching-overview-6</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/federal-trademark-searching-overview-6</guid>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day trademarks boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-18</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-18</guid>
	<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 10:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day trademarks boot camp on June 8 from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. CT at YWCA Metropolitan Chicago. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and startups in communities with limited or no internet access, covering what they should know about trademarks. The event explores what trademarks are, the benefits of federal trademark registration, and the basics of the registration process. We'll also discuss why it's so important for any new business to select a trademark that is both federally registrable and legally protectable. Topics will include: Fundamentals and searching Applications and filing Responses and registration There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information, questions about the one-day event, or the One-day patents and trademarks boot camp series, please email Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Attend DOCX filing training</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/attend-docx-filing-training-191</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/attend-docx-filing-training-191</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join us online June 11, 1-2 p. m. ET to learn how to file patent-related documents in DOCX format using Patent Center. You will hear from experts on our eCommerce Modernization (e Mod) team, who will provide demonstrations and answer your questions. This session is one of several free training sessions found on the DOCX filing series page. Instructions for joining the Webex training session will be provided via email to each registrant. DOCX is a word processing file format based on open standards and is supported by many popular word processing applications. As an open standard format, DOCX offers a safe and stable basis for authoring and processing intellectual property documents. Learn more about filing in DOCX in this hour-long session. We encourage you to explore DOCX filing using the Patent Center training mode at any time. Training mode does not save or store data in our systems. Register today For more information, please contact eMod@uspto.gov. To provide feedback, please visit the eMod Idea Scale. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Learn how to conduct a patent search at the USPTO Texas Regional Office</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/learn-how-conduct-patent-search-uspto-texas-regional-office-6</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/learn-how-conduct-patent-search-uspto-texas-regional-office-6</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 11:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you interested in learning more about patent searching? Register today to attend this in-person, interactive session on June 11 from 10-11:30 a. m. CT, led by United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) experts who will demonstrate how to conduct a patent search using the Patent Public Search tool. Participants will learn basic information about: How to conduct a preliminary U.S. patent search The six-step patentability search strategy Patent searching tools This new web-based patent search tool replaces legacy search tools Public-Examiner's Automated Search Tool (Pub East), Public-Web-based Examiner's Search Tool (Pub West), Patent Full-Text and Image Database (Pat FT), and Patent Application Full-Text and Image Database (App FT), which were retired in September 2022. Register today For more information about patent searching, visit the search for patents page on the USPTO website. For questions about this event, email the USPTO's Texas Regional Office at TexasRegionalOffice@uspto.gov or call 469-295-9000. Please feel free to bring your laptop and follow along. This event is strictly in-person and will not provide a virtual component. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day patents boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-13</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-13</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 10:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day patents boot camp on June 11, 2024 from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. CT at Discover Shine Bright Center in Chicago, IL. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and inventors in communities with limited or no internet access, covering tools, techniques, and resources to understand the patent application process. The event provides a scaffolded approach to understanding patents and intellectual property (IP) rights, the importance of claims in a patent application, and the various patent application requirements. It also includes: How to search prior art How to properly draft claims Understanding the application forms How to use Patent Center to file electronically There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information, questions about the one-day event or the One-day patent and trademark boot camp series, please email Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Federal trademark searching</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/federal-trademark-searching</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/federal-trademark-searching</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>LEAP to Chambers &#38;#8212; Detroit</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/leap-chambers-detroit</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/leap-chambers-detroit</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you new to practicing before the Patent Trial and Appeal Board (PTAB)? Sign up to attend LEAP to Chambers in the USPTO's Elijah J. Mc Coy Midwest Regional Office in Detroit. This event will take place in-person on Wednesday, June 12, 2024, 2-4:30 p. m. ET. The Legal Experience and Advancement Program, or LEAP, was created to help less experienced practitioners gain standup courtroom opportunities in PTAB ex parte appeal and AIA proceedings. The program also offers free legal training in oral advocacy skills. LEAP to Chambers provides LEAP-eligible practitioners an insider perspective on practicing before PTAB. These "LEAPers" will visit the Midwest Regional Office in Detroit for a PTAB judge-guided tour of PTAB's facilities. They will also learn oral and written advocacy tips from PTAB judges.  Preference will be given to LEAP-eligible attorneys and agents who have not participated in prior LEAP events. To participate, please apply by Monday, June 3, 2024. The purpose of this event is to facilitate small group interaction, so space is limited. If selected, you will be notified approximately one month before the event. Apply here More information about LEAP is available on our LEAP webpage. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Successful Inventing: Protection for your innovation</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/successful-inventing-protection-your-innovation</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/successful-inventing-protection-your-innovation</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you new to the invention process? If so, register today for the second event in the Successful Inventing series, presented by the United States Patent and Trademark Office and the Licensing Executives Society - Silicon Valley Chapter. The second session focuses on how to protect your innovation and will address the following topics: What is the advantage of a patent, trademark, or copyright? Should I hire a patent attorney or do it myself? What is the cost and timing? Register today The Successful Inventing series covers various aspects of the invention process. Each biweekly session is held virtually. Participants will hear experts discuss topics that include intellectual property (IP), product development, licensing, funding. A question-and-answer session will follow the presentation. Please send your questions in advance or during the event to SiliconValley@uspto.gov. For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Federal trademark searching</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/federal-trademark-searching-0</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/federal-trademark-searching-0</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 16:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Patents for librarians</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/patents-librarians-2</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/patents-librarians-2</guid>
	<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a librarian looking for a better understanding of patent concepts? Do you want to be able to share reliable resources with inventors looking to protect their intellectual property? The United States Patent and Trademark Office's Patent and Trademark Resource Center Program is offering a new webinar that introduces patent concepts and resources for professional librarians and library staff. This webinar will cover: An overview of patent concepts Types of patents Parts of a patent Steps to apply for a patent Patent and Trademark Resource Centers (PTRCs) and how they can help Additional resources Please register to attend this free virtual webinar, which will be held on Monday, June 17, from 2-3 p. m. ET. Register today For more information, email PTRCP@uspto.gov. Accessibility</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademarks for librarians</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademarks-librarians-2</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademarks-librarians-2</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a librarian looking for a better understanding of trademark concepts? Do you want to be able to share reliable resources with businesses looking to protect their intellectual property? The United States Patent and Trademark Office's Patent and Trademark Resource Center Program is offering a new webinar that introduces trademark concepts and resources for professional librarians and library staff. This webinar will cover: Types of trademarks Trademark application process Benefits of federal registration Common reasons for refusal USPTO resources Patent and Trademark Resource Centers (PTRCs) and how they can help Please register to attend this free virtual webinar, which will be held Tuesday, June 18, from 2-3 p. m. Eastern Time. Register today For more information, email PTRCP@uspto.gov. Accessibility</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Federal trademark searching: Overview</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/federal-trademark-searching-overview-7</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/federal-trademark-searching-overview-7</guid>
	<pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Learn the fundamentals of the patent application process</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/learn-fundamentals-patent-application-process-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/learn-fundamentals-patent-application-process-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you have an invention you want to patent? Are you unfamiliar with the patent filing process? Are you a first-time patent application filer or new to the Patent Center? Are you unsure where to start? Get a head St ART with this free, virtual three-day workshop that focuses on helping participants learn the fundamentals of the patent application process. The Stakeholder Application Readiness Training (St ART) is for independent inventors, entrepreneurs, and anyone working for or with a small business who want to file patent applications without the assistance of a registered patent agent or attorney. Patent protection is critical to: Safeguarding products and services from imitation Attracting and securing funding from outside investors Promoting the overall commercial success of any enterprise The St ART program is one of many initiatives and activities that form part of the USPTO's mission. Participants of the St ART three-day workshop will receive training from experts on the following subjects: Types of patent applications Prior art searches Scope of claims Formality requirements Claim writing and claim drafting Proper application forms (provisional, design, and non-provisional)Application data sheet Patent Center DOCX files Participants may also choose to participate in one-on-one assistance breakout room discussions. So you get the most out of the workshop if you are selected to attend, you must complete these course prerequisites beforehand: The Intellectual Property (IP) Awareness Survey to identify the type of patent that best fits your IP needs A written description and drawing(s) of your invention A USPTO customer number to track your application Creation of a verified My USPTO.gov account to gain access to better monitoring, tracking, and responses from the USPTO throughout the application process For assistance with obtaining a customer number and setting up a verified My USPTO.gov account, contact the Patent Electronic Business Center (EBC). Complete interest form Instructions for joining the training session are provided via email to each registrant. For more information, email setd@uspto.gov. If you are an individual with a disability and require reasonable accommodation to access this training, please email the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity and Diversity (OEEOD) at oeeod@uspto.gov or call 571-272-8292. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Learn the fundamentals of the patent application process</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/learn-fundamentals-patent-application-process-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/learn-fundamentals-patent-application-process-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you have an invention you want to patent? Are you unfamiliar with the patent filing process? Are you a first-time patent application filer or new to the Patent Center? Are you unsure where to start? Get a head St ART with this free, virtual three-day workshop that focuses on helping participants learn the fundamentals of the patent application process. The Stakeholder Application Readiness Training (St ART) is for independent inventors, entrepreneurs, and anyone working for or with a small business who want to file patent applications without the assistance of a registered patent agent or attorney. Patent protection is critical to: Safeguarding products and services from imitation Attracting and securing funding from outside investors Promoting the overall commercial success of any enterprise The St ART program is one of many initiatives and activities that form part of the USPTO's mission. Participants of the St ART three-day workshop will receive training from experts on the following subjects: Types of patent applications Prior art searches Scope of claims Formality requirements Claim writing and claim drafting Proper application forms (provisional, design, and non-provisional)Application data sheet Patent Center DOCX files Participants may also choose to participate in one-on-one assistance breakout room discussions. So you get the most out of the workshop if you are selected to attend, you must complete these course prerequisites beforehand: The Intellectual Property (IP) Awareness Survey to identify the type of patent that best fits your IP needs A written description and drawing(s) of your invention A USPTO customer number to track your application Creation of a verified My USPTO.gov account to gain access to better monitoring, tracking, and responses from the USPTO throughout the application process For assistance with obtaining a customer number and setting up a verified My USPTO.gov account, contact the Patent Electronic Business Center (EBC). Complete interest form Instructions for joining the training session are provided via email to each registrant. For more information, email setd@uspto.gov. If you are an individual with a disability and require reasonable accommodation to access this training, please email the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity and Diversity (OEEOD) at oeeod@uspto.gov or call 571-272-8292. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Successful Inventing: License or manufacture</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/successful-inventing-license-or-manufacture</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/successful-inventing-license-or-manufacture</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you new to the invention process? If so, register today for the third event in the Successful Inventing series, presented by the United States Patent and Trademark Office and the Licensing Executives Society - Silicon Valley Chapter. The third session focuses on licensing and manufacturing and will address the following topics: Pros and cons of licensing vs. manufacturing What companies need to see to license your product What can and cannot be licensed What you need to know to manufacture Register today The Successful Inventing series covers various aspects of the invention process. Each biweekly session is held virtually. Participants will hear experts discuss topics that include intellectual property, product development, licensing, funding. A question-and-answer session will follow the presentation. Please send your questions in advance or during the event to SiliconValley@uspto.gov. For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>PTAB Inventor Hour - Episode 29</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/ptab-inventor-hour-episode-29</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/ptab-inventor-hour-episode-29</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you an inventor, entrepreneur, new practitioner, or someone who wants to learn more about the United States Patent and Trademark Office and Patent Trial and Appeal Board (PTAB)? Join us Thursday, June 27, at noon ET for the next PTAB Inventor Hour webinar, Episode 29. This episode will feature special guests Jeffrey Fredman, John Schneider, and Amee Shah for our 'Meet our APJs' segment. Episode 29 will also feature: A review of a PTAB case file (Ex parte Walker, Appeal No. 2011-007593, U.S. application 10/981,365), including practice tips to help you succeed in ex parte appeals A walkthrough on how to access the USPTO's New to PTAB webpage A question-and-answer session will follow the presentation. Please send questions before or during the webinar to PTABInventorHour@uspto.gov. Register here</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Learn the fundamentals of the patent application process</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/learn-fundamentals-patent-application-process-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/learn-fundamentals-patent-application-process-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 09:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you have an invention you want to patent? Are you unfamiliar with the patent filing process? Are you a first-time patent application filer or new to the Patent Center? Are you unsure where to start? Get a head St ART with this free, virtual three-day workshop that focuses on helping participants learn the fundamentals of the patent application process. The Stakeholder Application Readiness Training (St ART) is for independent inventors, entrepreneurs, and anyone working for or with a small business who want to file patent applications without the assistance of a registered patent agent or attorney. Patent protection is critical to: Safeguarding products and services from imitation Attracting and securing funding from outside investors Promoting the overall commercial success of any enterprise The St ART program is one of many initiatives and activities that form part of the USPTO's mission. Participants of the St ART three-day workshop will receive training from experts on the following subjects: Types of patent applications Prior art searches Scope of claims Formality requirements Claim writing and claim drafting Proper application forms (provisional, design, and non-provisional)Application data sheet Patent Center DOCX files Participants may also choose to participate in one-on-one assistance breakout room discussions. So you get the most out of the workshop if you are selected to attend, you must complete these course prerequisites beforehand: The Intellectual Property (IP) Awareness Survey to identify the type of patent that best fits your IP needs A written description and drawing(s) of your invention A USPTO customer number to track your application Creation of a verified My USPTO.gov account to gain access to better monitoring, tracking, and responses from the USPTO throughout the application process For assistance with obtaining a customer number and setting up a verified My USPTO.gov account, contact the Patent Electronic Business Center (EBC). Complete interest form Instructions for joining the training session are provided via email to each registrant. For more information, email setd@uspto.gov. If you are an individual with a disability and require reasonable accommodation to access this training, please email the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity and Diversity (OEEOD) at oeeod@uspto.gov or call 571-272-8292. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Getting started with Patent Public Search</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/getting-started-patent-public-search-3</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/getting-started-patent-public-search-3</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you puzzled by patent searching or confused by the patent searching options available on the internet? Whether you are a novice searcher or an experienced one, the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) is here to help.  Librarians from the Patent and Trademark Resource Center Program, who are experienced with educating users on USPTO search tools, will show you how to use the new Patent Public Search tool. The virtual webinar will be held on Thursday, June 27, from 2-3 p. m. ET. Register today For more information about this webinar, please email PTRCP@uspto.gov. Accessibility</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Attend DOCX filing training</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/attend-docx-filing-training-190</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/attend-docx-filing-training-190</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join us online June 27, 2-3 p. m. ET to learn how to file patent-related documents in DOCX format using Patent Center. You will hear from experts on our eCommerce Modernization (e Mod) team, who will provide demonstrations and answer your questions. This session is one of several free training sessions found on the DOCX filing series page. Instructions for joining the Webex training session will be provided via email to each registrant. DOCX is a word processing file format based on open standards and is supported by many popular word processing applications. As an open standard format, DOCX offers a safe and stable basis for authoring and processing intellectual property documents. Learn more about filing in DOCX in this hour-long session. We encourage you to explore DOCX filing using the Patent Center training mode at any time. Training mode does not save or store data in our systems. Register today For more information, please contact eMod@uspto.gov. To provide feedback, please visit the eMod Idea Scale. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Successful Inventing: Product development</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/successful-inventing-product-development-0</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/successful-inventing-product-development-0</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you new to the invention process? If so, register today for the fourth event in the Successful Inventing series, presented by the United States Patent and Trademark Office and the Licensing Executives Society - Silicon Valley Chapter. During the fourth session, focused on product development, we will address the following topics: Product design vs. product engineering Design it, develop a complete product, sell it before you make it, obsolete the competition Determine what people want, before they know they want it What is your market advantage? Register today The Successful Inventing series covers various aspects of the invention process. Each biweekly session is held virtually. Participants will hear experts discuss topics that include intellectual property, product development, licensing, funding, and more. A question-and-answer session will follow the presentation. Please send your questions in advance or during the event to SiliconValley@uspto.gov. For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part I: IP basics</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-i-ip-basics-13</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-i-ip-basics-13</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you interested in learning about intellectual property (IP) basics? In part one of this eight-part recurring series, our experts will: Provide a brief overview of the different types of IP (patents, trademarks, trade secrets, and copyrights)Review the patenting process from invention, to application, to issue Cover the requirements for patentability Explain how to determine whether a provisional or nonprovisional application is right for you Discuss how to weigh the costs and benefits of hiring a patent attorney Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Attend DOCX filing training</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/attend-docx-filing-training-193</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/attend-docx-filing-training-193</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join us online July 11, 2-3 p. m. ET to learn how to file patent-related documents in DOCX format using Patent Center. You will hear from experts on our eCommerce Modernization (e Mod) team, who will provide demonstrations and answer your questions. This session is one of several free training sessions found on the DOCX filing series page. Instructions for joining the Webex training session will be provided via email to each registrant. DOCX is a word processing file format based on open standards and is supported by many popular word processing applications. As an open standard format, DOCX offers a safe and stable basis for authoring and processing intellectual property documents. Learn more about filing in DOCX in this hour-long session. We encourage you to explore DOCX filing using the Patent Center training mode at any time. Training mode does not save or store data in our systems. Register today For more information, please email eMod@uspto.gov. To provide feedback, please visit the eMod Idea Scale. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part II: Drafting provisional patent applications</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-ii-drafting-provisional-patent-applications-6</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-ii-drafting-provisional-patent-applications-6</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>In part two of this eight-part recurring series, our experts discuss key differences between provisional and nonprovisional patent applications, filing requirements and fees, the different ways to file a provisional application, and more. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Attend DOCX filing training</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/attend-docx-filing-training-192</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/attend-docx-filing-training-192</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join us online July 23, 1-2 p. m. ET to learn how to file patent-related documents in DOCX format using Patent Center. You will hear from experts on our eCommerce Modernization (e Mod) team, who will provide demonstrations and answer your questions. This session is one of several free training sessions found on the DOCX filing series page. Instructions for joining the Webex training session will be provided via email to each registrant. DOCX is a word processing file format based on open standards and is supported by many popular word processing applications. As an open standard format, DOCX offers a safe and stable basis for authoring and processing intellectual property documents. Learn more about filing in DOCX in this hour-long session. We encourage you to explore DOCX filing using the Patent Center training mode at any time. Training mode does not save or store data in our systems. Register today For more information, please email eMod@uspto.gov. To provide feedback, please visit the eMod Idea Scale. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Successful Inventing: Your elevator pitch and plan</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/successful-inventing-your-elevator-pitch-and-plan</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/successful-inventing-your-elevator-pitch-and-plan</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you new to the invention process? If so, register today for the fifth event in the Successful Inventing series, presented by the United States Patent and Trademark Office and the Licensing Executives Society - Silicon Valley Chapter. During the fifth session, focused on your elevator pitch and plan, we will address the following topics: What is your message? Short and to the point. What do companies expect to see from inventors? What companies to approach and why? What are the licensing odds for success? Register today The Successful Inventing series covers various aspects of the invention process. Each biweekly session is held virtually. Participants will hear experts discuss topics that include intellectual property, product development, licensing, funding, and more. A question-and-answer session will follow the presentation. Please send your questions in advance or during the event to SiliconValley@uspto.gov. For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part III: Patent searching</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-iii-patent-searching-8</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-iii-patent-searching-8</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you interested in learning more about patent searching? In part three of this eight-part recurring series, our experts will discuss preliminary searching using the suggested seven-step strategy and more. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part IV: Learn how to draft a patent application</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-iv-learn-how-draft-patent-application-7</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-iv-learn-how-draft-patent-application-7</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Understanding patent application drafting is a vital step in protecting your invention. In part four of this eight-part recurring series, our experts will discuss the formalities and requirements of drafting a patent application, as well as how to avoid common mistakes. To gain the most from this workshop, we suggest participants have an intermediate knowledge of the intellectual property (IP) system in general, and patents specifically. We recommend that you take the previous course in the series, Part I: IP basics, prior to registering for this webinar. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Successful Inventing: Early-stage funding</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/successful-inventing-early-stage-funding-0</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/successful-inventing-early-stage-funding-0</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you new to the invention process? If so, register today for the sixth virtual event in the Successful Inventing series, presented by the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) and the Licensing Executives Society - Silicon Valley Chapter (LES-SVC). The sixth session focuses on early-stage funding and will address the following: The 4-F's, angels, venture, and banks Informal, formal, and growth business plans Federal and state grants and resources Incubators and accelerators How you will reach the customer Why and how it will succeed Register today The Successful Inventing series covers various aspects of the invention process. Each biweekly session is held virtually. Participants will hear experts discuss topics that include intellectual property (IP), product development, licensing, funding, and more. A question-and-answer session will follow the presentation. Please send your questions in advance or during the event to SiliconValley@uspto.gov. For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part V: Understanding the role of claims in a patent application</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-v-understanding-role-claims-patent-application-6</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-v-understanding-role-claims-patent-application-6</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you an inventor preparing to file a patent application? In part five of this eight-part recurring series, our experts will discuss the parts of the claim, show examples of claim illustrations from issued U.S. patents, and help participants develop a better appreciation of how a patent examiner views a claim. To get the most out of this workshop, you should have an intermediate knowledge of the intellectual property (IP) system and of patents specifically. We recommend that you complete the previous sessions in the series, Part I: IP basics and Part IV: Learn how to draft your patent application, before attending. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day trademarks boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-21</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-21</guid>
	<pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day trademarks boot camp on August 17, 2024 from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. HT at Kaua'i Community College in Lihue, HI. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and startups in communities with limited or no internet access, covering what they should know about trademarks. The event explores what trademarks are, the benefits of federal trademark registration, and the basics of the registration process. We'll also discuss why it's so important for any new business to select a trademark that is both federally registrable and legally protectable. Specific topics include: Fundamentals and searching Applications and filing Responses and registration There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information, questions about the one-day event, or the One-day patents and trademarks boot camp series, please email Andriae Holt at Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day patents boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-17</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-17</guid>
	<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day patents boot camp on August 19, 2024, from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. HT at Kuha&#x 02 BB;o Business Center in Kahului, Hawaii. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and inventors in communities with limited or no internet access, covering tools, techniques, and resources to understand the patent application process. The event provides a scaffolded approach to understanding patents and intellectual property (IP) rights, the importance of claims in a patent application, and the various patent application requirements. It also includes: How to search prior art How to properly draft claims Understanding the application forms How to use Patent Center to file electronically There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information and questions about this event or the One-day patent and trademark boot camp series, please email Andriae M. Holt at Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day trademarks boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-20</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-20</guid>
	<pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day trademarks boot camp on August 19, 2024 from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. HT at Hale Iako Incubator/Office Building in Kailua-Kona, HI. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and startups in communities with limited or no internet access, covering what they should know about trademarks. The event explores what trademarks are, the benefits of federal trademark registration, and the basics of the registration process. We'll also discuss why it's so important for any new business to select a trademark that is both federally registrable and legally protectable. Specific topics include: Fundamentals and searching Applications and filing Responses and registration There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information, questions about the one-day event, or the One-day patents and trademarks boot camp series, please email Andriae Holt at Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day patents boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-15</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-15</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day patents boot camp on August 20, 2024, from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. HT at Hale Iako Incubator/Office Building in Kailua-Kona, HI. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and inventors in communities with limited or no internet access, covering tools, techniques, and resources to understand the patent application process. The event provides a scaffolded approach to understanding patents and intellectual property (IP) rights, the importance of claims in a patent application, and the various patent application requirements. It also includes: How to search prior art How to properly draft claims Understanding the application forms How to use Patent Center to file electronically There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information, questions about the one-day event or the One-day patent and trademark boot camp series, please email Andriae M. Holt at Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day trademarks boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-25</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-25</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day trademarks boot camp on August 20, 2024, from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. HT at Kuha'o Business Center in Kahului, Hawaii. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and startups in communities with limited or no internet access, covering what they should know about trademarks. The event explores what trademarks are, the benefits of federal trademark registration, and the basics of the registration process. We'll also discuss why it's so important for any new business to select a trademark that is both federally registrable and legally protectable. Specific topics include: Fundamentals and searching Applications and filing Responses and registration There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information, questions about the one-day event, or the One-day patents and trademarks boot camp series, please email Andriae Holt at Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day trademarks boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-23</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-23</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day trademarks boot camp on August 21, 2024 from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. HT at Entrepreneurs Sandbox in Honolulu, HI. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and startups in communities with limited or no internet access, covering what they should know about trademarks. The event explores what trademarks are, the benefits of federal trademark registration, and the basics of the registration process. We'll also discuss why it's so important for any new business to select a trademark that is both federally registrable and legally protectable. Specific topics include: Fundamentals and searching Applications and filing Responses and registration There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information, questions about the one-day event, or the One-day patents and trademarks boot camp series, please email Andriae Holt at Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day patents boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-18</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-18</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day patents boot camp on August 21, 2024, from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. HT at Kuha'o Business Center in Kaunakakai, Hawaii. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and inventors in communities with limited or no internet access, covering tools, techniques, and resources to understand the patent application process. The event provides a scaffolded approach to understanding patents and intellectual property (IP) rights, the importance of claims in a patent application, and the various patent application requirements. It also includes: How to search prior art How to properly draft claims Understanding the application forms How to use Patent Center to file electronically There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information and questions about this event or the One-day patent and trademark boot camp series, please email Andriae M. Holt at Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VI: Learn how to protect your IP abroad</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vi-learn-how-protect-your-ip-abroad-6</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vi-learn-how-protect-your-ip-abroad-6</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Did you know that patents offer territorial rights, meaning that there is no such thing as an international or global patent? Learn how to help protect your intellectual property (IP) in foreign jurisdictions. In part six of this eight-part recurring series, International Patent Legal Administration experts will discuss considerations and options for filing foreign patent applications. The discussion will include an overview of the Patent Cooperation Treaty (PCT) and the use of the Paris Convention for non-PCT countries. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day patents boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-16</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-16</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day patents boot camp on August 22, 2024, from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. HT at HTDC-Entrepreneurs Sandbox in Honolulu, HI. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and inventors in communities with limited or no internet access, covering tools, techniques, and resources to understand the patent application process. The event provides a scaffolded approach to understanding patents and intellectual property (IP) rights, the importance of claims in a patent application, and the various patent application requirements. It also includes: How to search prior art How to properly draft claims Understanding the application forms How to use Patent Center to file electronically There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information, questions about the one-day event or the One-day patent and trademark boot camp series, please email Andriae M. Holt at Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day trademarks boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-24</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-24</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day trademarks boot camp on August 22, 2024, from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. HT at Kuha&#x 02 BB;o Business Center in Kaunakakai, Hawaii. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and startups in communities with limited or no internet access, covering what they should know about trademarks. The event explores what trademarks are, the benefits of federal trademark registration, and the basics of the registration process. We'll also discuss why it's so important for any new business to select a trademark that is both federally registrable and legally protectable. Specific topics include: Fundamentals and searching Applications and filing Responses and registration There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information and questions about this event or the One-day patents and trademarks boot camp series, please email Andriae Holt at Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day patents boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-19</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-19</guid>
	<pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day patents boot camp on August 24, 2024, from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. HT at Kaua'i Community College in Lihue, Hawaii. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and inventors in communities with limited or no internet access, covering tools, techniques, and resources to understand the patent application process. The event provides a scaffolded approach to understanding patents and intellectual property (IP) rights, the importance of claims in a patent application, and the various patent application requirements. It also includes: Specific topics include: How to search prior art How to properly draft claims Understanding the application forms How to use Patent Center to file electronically There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information and questions about this event or the One-day patents and trademarks boot camp series, please email Andriae Holt at Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VII: How to file a patent application using Patent Center</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vii-how-file-patent-application-using-patent-center-6</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vii-how-file-patent-application-using-patent-center-6</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Looking for more information on using Patent Center? In part seven of this eight-part recurring series, our experts will teach participants how to use this tool to file and manage patent documents online. This presentation will feature filing application documents in DOCX format, including using Patent Center training mode to practice filing. You will learn about some helpful resources, such as the Inventors Assistance Center (IAC) and the Patent Electronics Business Center (EBC). Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VIII: Common mistakes and post-filing support</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-viii-common-mistakes-and-post-filing-support-6</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-viii-common-mistakes-and-post-filing-support-6</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you an inventor? Join us for this session full of important tips on filing a patent application and what to do after you file for a patent. In the final part of this eight-part recurring series, you will learn about common mistakes to avoid, and you'll gain a better understanding of post-filing procedures and support. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day patents boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-14</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-patents-boot-camp-14</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 09:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day patents boot camp on September 19, 2024, from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. ET at the Ohio State Research Commons in the 18th Avenue Library in Columbus, OH. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and inventors in communities with limited or no internet access, covering tools, techniques, and resources to understand the patent application process. The event provides a scaffolded approach to understanding patents and intellectual property (IP) rights, the importance of claims in a patent application, and the various patent application requirements. It also includes: How to search prior art How to properly draft claims Understanding the application forms How to use Patent Center to file electronically There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information, questions about the one-day event or the One-day patent and trademark boot camp series, please email Andriae M. Holt at Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>One-day trademarks boot camp</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-19</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/one-day-trademarks-boot-camp-19</guid>
	<pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 09:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for a one-day trademarks boot camp on September 20, 2024 from 9 a. m. to 5 p. m. ET at Columbus Metropolitan Library-Downtown Branch in Columbus, OH. This is an in-person, single-day workshop for entrepreneurs, small businesses, and startups in communities with limited or no internet access, covering what they should know about trademarks. The event explores what trademarks are, the benefits of federal trademark registration, and the basics of the registration process. We'll also discuss why it's so important for any new business to select a trademark that is both federally registrable and legally protectable. Specific topics include: Fundamentals and searching Applications and filing Responses and registration There will be plenty of question-and-answer sessions throughout the day, plus a discussion about free resources available through the USPTO. This event is free, but registration is required. For registration information, questions about the one-day event, or the One-day patents and trademarks boot camp series, please email Andriae Holt at Andriae. Holt@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
</channel>
</rss>