<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
 <title>USPTO Trademark Events</title>
<link>https://guides.lib.ucr.edu/c.php?g=932732</link>
 <description>This feed provides easy access to USPTO Trademark events.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
 <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 09:22:13 PST</lastBuildDate>
<webManager>katherine.koziar@ucr.edu</webManager>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 1: Fundamentals</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-1-fundamentals-14</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-1-fundamentals-14</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this first module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll focus on trademark protection in the United States. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early.This module will cover the following topics:Definitions and types of trademarksBenefits of federal registrationSelecting a trademarkFiling and registrationFinding help This module will be presented live via Webex from 2-3:30 p.m. ET on Tuesday, January 9, 2024, and will conclude with a question-and-answer session. Please register by January 8. Register todayBe sure to check out our other boot camp modules running consecutively every week for the eight-week duration. You can attend the whole series or just the specific modules that best meet your needs. Separate registration is required for each module. After each event, we'll email registrants links to a video recording of the module and a PDF of the presentation materials. You will only receive access to the recording if you are signed up for that module.For questions about the event or the boot camp series, please contact TMWebinar@uspto.gov.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 2: Registration process overview</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-2-registration-process-overview-10</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-2-registration-process-overview-10</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this second module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll focus on the overall trademark registration process, from filing to registration. Understanding the process is critical to avoid missing any filing deadlines, which could jeopardize your application or registration. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early.In this module, we will cover the following topics:Trademark basicsApplication workflow and timeline overviewPost-registration workflow overviewFinding helpThis module will be presented live via Webex from 2-3:30 p.m. ET on Tuesday, January 16, 2024, and will conclude with a question-and-answer session. Please register by January 15.Register todayBe sure to check out our other boot camp modules running consecutively every week for the eight-week duration. You can attend the whole series or just the specific modules that best meet your needs. Separate registration is required for each module. After each event, we'll email registrants links to a video recording of the module and a PDF of the presentation materials. You will only receive access to the recording if you are signed up for that module.For questions about the event or the boot camp series, please contact TMWebinar@uspto.gov.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 3: Searching</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-3-searching-10</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-3-searching-10</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this third module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll focus on important principles related to federal trademark clearance searching and effective use of the USPTO's trademark database. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early.This module will cover the following topics:Trademark basicsLikelihood of confusionFederal trademark searchingFinding help  This module will be presented live via Webex from 2-3:30 p.m. ET on Tuesday, January 23, 2024, and will conclude with a question-and-answer session. Please register by January 22.Register todayBe sure to check out our other boot camp modules running consecutively every week for the eight-week duration. You can attend the whole series or just the specific modules that best meet your needs. Separate registration is required for each module. After each event, we'll email registrants links to a video recording of the module and a PDF of the presentation materials. You will only receive access to the recording if you are signed up for that module.For questions about the event or the boot camp series, please contact TMWebinar@uspto.gov.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 4: Application requirements</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-4-application-requirements-10</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-4-application-requirements-10</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this fourth module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll focus on the requirements for an initial trademark application. Knowing what is needed up front will help your filing process go more smoothly. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early. This module will cover the following topics:Trademark basicsDrawingsIdentifications of goods and servicesFiling basesSpecimens and ornamentationFinding helpThis module will be presented live via Webex from 2-3:30 p.m. ET on Tuesday, January 30, 2024, and will conclude with a question-and-answer session. Please register by January 29. Register todayBe sure to check out our other boot camp modules running consecutively every week for the eight-week duration. You can attend the whole series or just the specific modules that best meet your needs. Separate registration is required for each module. After each event, we'll email registrants links to a video recording of the module and a PDF of the presentation materials. You will only receive access to the recording if you are signed up for that module.For questions about the event or the boot camp series, please contact TMWebinar@uspto.gov.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 5: Application filing walk-through</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-5-application-filing-walk-through-10</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-5-application-filing-walk-through-10</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this fifth module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll focus on the USPTO's Trademark Electronic Application System (TEAS), including a live demonstration of a trademark filing. TEAS is the required system for making any trademark submission to the USPTO. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early.This module will cover the following topics:Trademark basicsTEAS basicsTEAS pre-filing checklistTEAS Plus demonstrationFinding helpThis module will be presented live via Webex from 2-3:30 p.m. ET on Tuesday, February 6, 2024, and will conclude with a question-and-answer session. Please register by February 5.Register todayBe sure to check out our other boot camp modules running consecutively every week for the eight-week duration. You can attend the whole series or just the specific modules that best meet your needs. Separate registration is required for each module. After each event, we'll email registrants links to a video recording of the module and a PDF of the presentation materials. You will only receive access to the recording if you are signed up for that module.For questions about the event or the boot camp series, please contact TMWebinar@uspto.gov.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 6: Responding to an office action</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-6-responding-office-action-10</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-6-responding-office-action-10</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this sixth module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll focus on responding to office actions, the official letters that USPTO examining attorneys issue after reviewing your trademark application. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early.This module will cover the following topics:Trademark basicsOffice action basicsResponse timeframes and deadlinesFiling a responseTips for a successful responseFinding helpThis module will be presented live via Webex from 2-3:30 p.m. ET on Tuesday, February 13, 2024, and will conclude with a question-and-answer session. Please register by February 12. Register todayBe sure to check out our other boot camp modules running consecutively every week for the eight-week duration. You can attend the whole series or just the specific modules that best meet your needs. Separate registration is required for each module. After each event, we'll email registrants links to a video recording of the module and a PDF of the presentation materials. You will only receive access to the recording if you are signed up for that module.For questions about the event or the boot camp series, please contact TMWebinar@uspto.gov.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 7: Keeping your registration alive</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-7-keeping-your-registration-alive-13</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-7-keeping-your-registration-alive-13</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this seventh module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll focus on what happens after registration, including mandatory filings to keep your registration alive. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early.This module will cover the following topics:Trademark basicsRequired post-registration filingsOptional post-registration filingsExamination of post-registration filingsFinding helpThis module will be presented live via Webex from 2-3:30 p.m. ET on Tuesday, February 20, 2024, and will conclude with a question-and-answer session. Please register by February 19.Register todayBe sure to check out our other boot camp modules running consecutively every week for the eight-week duration. You can attend the whole series or just the specific modules that best meet your needs. Separate registration is required for each module. After each event, we'll email registrants links to a video recording of the module and a PDF of the presentation materials. You will only receive access to the recording if you are signed up for that module.For questions about the event or the boot camp series, please contact TMWebinar@uspto.gov.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 8: Question-and-answer panel</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-8-question-and-answer-panel-12</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-8-question-and-answer-panel-12</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this final module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll provide a unique opportunity for you to 'meet the trademark experts.' Come prepared with all of your trademark questions to share with our Law Office Managing Attorneys and other trademark experts. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early.This module will be presented live via Webex from 2-3:30 p.m. ET on Tuesday, February 27, 2024. Please register by February 26. Register todayBe sure to check out our other boot camp modules running consecutively every week for the eight-week duration. You can attend the whole series or just the specific modules that best meet your needs. Separate registration is required for each module. After each event, we'll email registrants links to a video recording of the module and a PDF of the presentation materials. You will only receive access to the recording if you are signed up for that module.For questions about the event or the boot camp series, please contact TMWebinar@uspto.gov.</description>
</item>

 
</channel>
</rss>