<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
 <title>USPTO All Events</title>
<link>https://guides.lib.ucr.edu/c.php?g=932732</link>
 <description>This feed provides easy access to USPTO All events.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
 <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 12:44:24 PST</lastBuildDate>
<webManager>katherine.koziar@ucr.edu</webManager>

 
<item> <title>Empowering Innovations: Celebrating Hispanic pioneers in education and invention</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/empowering-innovations-celebrating-hispanic-pioneers-education-invention</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/empowering-innovations-celebrating-hispanic-pioneers-education-invention</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 18:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>This event on November 28 was originally scheduled for October 31. Please refer to this listing for updates and information.Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office's (USPTO) Office of Education for an illuminating Fireside Chat on Innovation from the Hispanic community. Tune in to this webinar on Tuesday, November 28, from 6-7:30 p.m. ET as we delve deep into the intricate dance of innovation, invention, and mentorship.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Empowering Innovations: Celebrating Hispanic pioneers in education and invention</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/empowering-innovations-celebrating-hispanic-pioneers-education-invention</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/empowering-innovations-celebrating-hispanic-pioneers-education-invention</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 18:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>This event on November 28 was originally scheduled for October 31. Please refer to this listing for updates and information.Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office's (USPTO) Office of Education for an illuminating Fireside Chat on Innovation from the Hispanic community. Tune in to this webinar on Tuesday, November 28, from 6-7:30 p.m. ET as we delve deep into the intricate dance of innovation, invention, and mentorship.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>K-12 education office hours</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/k-12-education-office-hours-8</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/k-12-education-office-hours-8</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 15:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Roundtable discussion: Tribes, intellectual property, and consumer protection</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/roundtable-discussion-tribes-intellectual-property-and-consumer-protection</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/roundtable-discussion-tribes-intellectual-property-and-consumer-protection</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 09:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Patent Public Advisory Committee public meeting</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/patent-public-advisory-committee-public-meeting-6</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/patent-public-advisory-committee-public-meeting-6</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 10:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Attend the next public meeting of the United States Patent and Trademark Office's (USPTO) Patent Public Advisory Committee (PPAC) to learn more about patent-related policies, goals, performance, budgets, and user fees. You can watch the virtual public session via WebEx. The PPAC advises the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the USPTO. The public meeting agenda will be available one week before the scheduled meeting.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VII: How to file a patent application using Patent Center</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vii-how-file-patent-application-using-patent-center-3</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vii-how-file-patent-application-using-patent-center-3</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Looking for more information on using Patent Center? In part seven of this eight-part recurring series, United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) experts will teach participants how to use this tool to file and manage patent documents online.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Fashion, Beauty, and Intellectual Property: Fashion law and social justice inclusion in IP</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/fashion-beauty-and-intellectual-property-fashion-law-and-social-justice-inclusion</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/fashion-beauty-and-intellectual-property-fashion-law-and-social-justice-inclusion</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 16:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Learn how to conduct a patent search at the USPTO Texas Regional Office</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/learn-how-conduct-patent-search-uspto-texas-regional-office-3</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/learn-how-conduct-patent-search-uspto-texas-regional-office-3</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 11:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you interested in learning more about patent searching?Register today to attend this in-person, interactive session on December 5 from 10-11:30 a.m. CT, led by United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) experts who will demonstrate how to conduct a patent search using the Patent Public Search tool.Participants will learn basic information about:Conducting a preliminary U.S. patent searchThe six-step patentability search strategyPatent searching toolsThis new web-based patent search tool replaces legacy search tools Public-Examiner's Automated Search Tool (PubEast), Public-Web-based Examiner's Search Tool (PubWest), Patent Full-Text and Image Database (PatFT), and Patent Application Full-Text and Image Database (AppFT), which were retired in September 2022.Register todayFor more information about patent searching, visit the search for patents page on the USPTO website.For questions about this event, email the USPTO's Texas Regional Office at TexasRegionalOffice@uspto.gov or call 469-295-9000. Please feel free to bring your laptop and follow along. This event is strictly in-person and will not provide a virtual component.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Intellectual Property Basics and Helpful Resources</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/intellectual-property-basics-and-helpful-resources-cloned-2</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/intellectual-property-basics-and-helpful-resources-cloned-2</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Unfamiliar with patents, trademarks, copyrights, and trade secrets? Don't miss this opportunity to learn from USPTO experts about intellectual property (IP) basics and potential ways to protect your innovation as you transition from idea to product.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VIII: Common mistakes and post-filing support</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-viii-common-mistakes-and-post-filing-support-3</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-viii-common-mistakes-and-post-filing-support-3</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you an inventor? Join us for this session full of important tips on filing a patent application and what to do after you file for a patent.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Ex Parte Appeal Roadshows - Los Angeles</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/ex-parte-appeal-roadshows-los-angeles-california</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/ex-parte-appeal-roadshows-los-angeles-california</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 16:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a Patent Trial and Appeal Board (PTAB) practitioner? Would you like to learn more about ex parte appeal proceedings directly from PTAB judges? Attend an Ex Parte Appeal Roadshow.The PTAB is holding in-person training focusing on best practices to succeed in an appeal on Thursday, December 7, at the Los Angeles Central Library from 1-5 p.m. PT. PTAB judges will teach all sessions. Topics include:Tips to file an appeal brief efficientlyHow to make written arguments more persuasiveHow to present an effective oral argument before a judge panelSee the agenda for more information. The event is free and registration is encouraged. The Ex Parte Appeal Roadshow will also take place in Austin, Atlanta, Indianapolis, and Philadelphia. See the full schedule for dates. If you have any questions regarding this event, please email PTABEvents@uspto.gov.CLE credit is pending per state for each roadshow location.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-0</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-0</guid>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on December 11 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Getting started with Patent Public Search</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/learning-and-resources/researchers-librarians/getting-started-patent-public-search-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/learning-and-resources/researchers-librarians/getting-started-patent-public-search-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you puzzled by patent searching or confused by the patent searching options available on the internet? Whether you are a novice searcher or an experienced one, the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) is here to help.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A fireside chat with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-0</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-0</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Come join us for a laid back and informational fireside chat that will give you an inside look at being a patent examiner at the USPTO. You will get the opportunity to engage in insightful conversations and get answers to your questions directly from team members.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Ex Parte Appeal Roadshows - Austin, Texas</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/ex-parte-appeal-roadshows-austin-texas</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/ex-parte-appeal-roadshows-austin-texas</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a Patent Trial and Appeal Board (PTAB) practitioner? Would you like to learn more about ex parte appeal proceedings directly from PTAB judges? Attend an Ex Parte Appeal Roadshow.The PTAB is holding in-person training focusing on best practices to succeed in an appeal on Thursday, February 1, at the University of Texas School of Law from 1-5 p.m. CT. PTAB judges will teach all sessions. Topics include:Tips to file an appeal brief efficientlyHow to make written arguments more persuasiveHow to present an effective oral argument before a judge panelSee the agenda for more information. The event is free and registration is encouraged. The Ex Parte Appeal Roadshow will also take place in Los Angeles, Atlanta, Indianapolis, and Philadelphia. See the full schedule for dates. If you have any questions regarding this event, please email PTABEvents@uspto.gov.CLE credit is pending per state for each roadshow location.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-1</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-1</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on February 6 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Ex Parte Appeal Roadshows - Atlanta</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/ex-parte-appeal-roadshows-atlanta-georgia</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/ex-parte-appeal-roadshows-atlanta-georgia</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a Patent Trial and Appeal Board (PTAB) practitioner? Would you like to learn more about ex parte appeal proceedings directly from PTAB judges? Attend an Ex Parte Appeal Roadshow.The PTAB is holding in-person training focusing on best practices to succeed in an appeal on Thursday, February 29, at the Emory School of Law from 1-5 p.m. ET. PTAB judges will teach all sessions. Topics include:Tips to file an appeal brief efficientlyHow to make written arguments more persuasiveHow to present an effective oral argument before a judge panelSee the agenda for more information. The event is free and registration is encouraged. The Ex Parte Appeal Roadshow will also take place in Los Angeles, Austin, Indianapolis, and Philadelphia. See the full schedule for dates. If you have any questions regarding this event, please email PTABEvents@uspto.gov.CLE credit is pending per state for each roadshow location.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-2</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-2</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on March 28 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Ex Parte Appeal Roadshows - Indianapolis, Indiana</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/ex-parte-appeal-roadshows-indianapolis-indiana</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/ex-parte-appeal-roadshows-indianapolis-indiana</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a Patent Trial and Appeal Board (PTAB) practitioner? Would you like to learn more about ex parte appeal proceedings directly from PTAB judges? Attend an Ex Parte Appeal Roadshow.The PTAB is holding in-person training focusing on best practices to succeed in an appeal on Thursday, April 4, at the Indianapolis Central Library from 1-5 p.m. ET. PTAB judges will teach all sessions. Topics include:Tips to file an appeal brief efficientlyHow to make written arguments more persuasiveHow to present an effective oral argument before a judge panelSee the agenda for more information. The event is free and registration is encouraged. The Ex Parte Appeal Roadshow will also take place in Los Angeles, Austin, Atlanta, and Philadelphia. See the full schedule for dates. If you have any questions regarding this event, please email PTABEvents@uspto.gov.CLE credit is pending per state for each roadshow location.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A fireside chat with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-1</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-1</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Come join us for a laid back and informational fireside chat that will give you an inside look at being a patent examiner at the USPTO. You will get the opportunity to engage in insightful conversations and get answers to your questions directly from team members.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Ex Parte Appeal Roadshows - Philadelphia</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/ex-parte-appeal-roadshows-philadelphia-pennsylvania</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/ex-parte-appeal-roadshows-philadelphia-pennsylvania</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a Patent Trial and Appeal Board (PTAB) practitioner? Would you like to learn more about ex parte appeal proceedings directly from PTAB judges? Attend an Ex Parte Appeal Roadshow.The PTAB is holding in-person training focusing on best practices to succeed in an appeal on Thursday, May 2, at the Free Library of Philadelphia from 1-5 p.m. ET. PTAB judges will teach all sessions. Topics include:Tips to file an appeal brief efficientlyHow to make written arguments more persuasiveHow to present an effective oral argument before a judge panelSee the agenda for more information. The event is free and registration is encouraged. The Ex Parte Appeal Roadshow will also take place in Los Angeles, Austin, Atlanta, and Indianapolis. See the full schedule for dates. If you have any questions regarding this event, please email PTABEvents@uspto.gov.CLE credit is pending per state for each roadshow location.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-3</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-3</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on May 15 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A fireside chat with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-2</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-2</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Come join us for a laid back and informational fireside chat that will give you an inside look at being a patent examiner at the USPTO. You will get the opportunity to engage in insightful conversations and get answers to your questions directly from team members.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on July 9 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner.</description>
</item>

 
</channel>
</rss>