<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
 <title>USPTO Trademark Events</title>
<link>https://guides.lib.ucr.edu/c.php?g=932732</link>
 <description>This feed provides easy access to USPTO Trademark events.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
 <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 19:30:11 PST</lastBuildDate>
<webMaster>katherine.koziar@ucr.edu</webMaster>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 5: Application filing walk-through</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-5-application-filing-walk-through-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-5-application-filing-walk-through-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this fifth module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll focus on the USPTO's Trademark Electronic Application System (TEAS), including a live demonstration of a trademark filing. TEAS is the required system for making any trademark submission to the USPTO. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Public Advisory Committee quarterly meeting</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/organizational-offices/public-advisory-committees/trademark-public-advisory-committee-11</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/organizational-offices/public-advisory-committees/trademark-public-advisory-committee-11</guid>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 10:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Attend the next quarterly meeting of the United States Patent and Trademark Office's (USPTO) Trademark Public Advisory Committee (TPAC) to learn more about trademark-related policies, goals, performance, budgets, and user fees. The TPAC advises the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the USPTO. The public meeting agenda will be available one week before the scheduled meeting.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Public Advisory Committee quarterly meeting</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/organizational-offices/public-advisory-committees/trademark-public-advisory-committee-11</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/organizational-offices/public-advisory-committees/trademark-public-advisory-committee-11</guid>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 10:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Attend the next quarterly meeting of the United States Patent and Trademark Office's (USPTO) Trademark Public Advisory Committee (TPAC) to learn more about trademark-related policies, goals, performance, budgets, and user fees. The TPAC advises the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the USPTO. The public meeting agenda will be available one week before the scheduled meeting.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 6: Responding to an office action</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-6-responding-office-action-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-6-responding-office-action-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this sixth module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll focus on responding to office actions, the official letters that USPTO examining attorneys issue after reviewing your trademark application. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 7: Keeping your registration alive</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-7-keeping-your-registration-alive-8</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-7-keeping-your-registration-alive-8</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this seventh module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll focus on what happens after registration, including mandatory filings to keep your registration alive. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early.</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Trademark Basics Boot Camp, Module 8: Question-and-answer panel</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-8-question-and-answer-panel-7</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/trademark-basics-boot-camp-module-8-question-and-answer-panel-7</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you a small business owner or entrepreneur interested in learning about trademarks and how to apply for a federal registration? If so, this event is a must-attend. In this final module of our eight-part virtual Trademark Basics Boot Camp, we'll provide a unique opportunity for you to 'meet the trademark experts.' Come prepared with all of your trademark questions to share with our Law Office Managing Attorneys and other trademark experts. The event is free, but space is limited, so register early.</description>
</item>

 
</channel>
</rss>