<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
 <title>USPTO Other Events</title>
<link>https://guides.lib.ucr.edu/c.php?g=932732</link>
 <description>This feed provides easy access to USPTO Other events.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
 <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 13:55:42 PST</lastBuildDate>
<webManager>katherine.koziar@ucr.edu</webManager>

 
<item> <title>17th annual USPTO-GIPC IP attach&#38;#233; roundtable</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/ip-policy/ip-attache-program/17th-annual-uspto-gipc-ip-attache-roundtable</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/ip-policy/ip-attache-program/17th-annual-uspto-gipc-ip-attache-roundtable</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 08:30:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>The 17th annual IP attach&#38;#233; roundtable, hosted by the U.S. Chamber of Commerce's Global Innovation Policy Center (GIPC), will feature presentations by each of the United States Patent and Trademark Office's (USPTO) intellectual property (IP) attach&#38;#233;s. A question-and-answer session will follow the presentations. The program will provide a unique opportunity to participate in an in-depth discussion of recent trends and challenges in IP protection and enforcement around the world. This in-person event is free and open to public. However, space is limited, so advance registration is required. Learn more about the USPTO's IP Attach&#38;#233; Program. Register today Additional information For more information, go to the registration page. For non-press inquiries, please contact Terri Davis at the USPTO's Office of Policy and International Affairs, or Kelly Anderson at the Global Innovation Policy Center. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>2023 Veterans Innovation and Entrepreneurship Program</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/2023-veterans-innovation-and-entrepreneurship-program</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/2023-veterans-innovation-and-entrepreneurship-program</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want to learn more about launching, growing, and protecting your business? Are you interested in learning about how trademarks, logos, and branding can help you on your journey? Join us on December 14 from 1 &#38;#8212; 3 p. m. ET for the 2023 Veterans Innovation and Entrepreneurship program. This event is open to all, and we encourage everyone who is affiliated with the military to attend. Don't miss this opportunity to hear from innovative veterans about their journeys towards successful entrepreneurship. You'll also learn about critical resources available to the military community, including training, mentoring, and how veterans and military spouses continued their service as innovators, entrepreneurs, and authors. Part one: Introduction United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) leadership greetings Congressional remarks Part two: Trademark Basics: What Every Brand Should Know Now, Not Later Part three: Veteran innovators, their journeys with IP and resources for the military community Agenda(All times Eastern Time, subject to change)December 14 Time Topic Speaker 1 &#38;#8212; 1:04 p. m. Introduction Program welcome and overview Ed Carballo, U.S. Army Veteran; Innovation Outreach Specialist &#38;#8212; National Programs, USPTO 1:05 &#38;#8212; 1:08 p. m. USPTO leadership greeting Dorene Matheis, Chief Learning Officer and Enterprise Training Division Chief, Office of Human Resources, USPTO and U.S. Army Veteran 1:08 &#38;#8212; 1:10 p. m. Congressional Remarks Representative Mikie Sherrill, NJ-11th District, U.S. Navy Veteran 1:10 &#38;#8212; 1:50 Featured Speaker Learn what every solo-entrepreneur, start-up, small business, and innovator should know about trademarks, logos, and branding. We'll discuss what trademarks are, the benefits of federal trademark registration, and the basics of the registration process. We'll also talk about why it's so important for any new business to select a trademark that is both federally registrable and legally protectable. Jason Lott, Managing Attorney for Trademarks Customer Outreach, USPTO 1:50 &#38;#8212; 1:55 p. m. Break and introduction Ed Carballo, U.S. Army Veteran, Innovation Outreach Specialist &#38;#8212; National Programs, Office of Innovation Outreach, USPTO 1:55 &#38;#8212; 2:40 p. m. Panel Discussion: Resources for Veterans &#38; Military Families Hear from a leading resource partner, focused on veterans and the military community, who provides critical assistance and resources for Innovators and Entrepreneurs. Brenton (Brent) Peacock, Director, Veterans Business Outreach Center (VBOC) at Gulf Coast State College Randall Shepard, Founder &#38; CEO of RSAE Labs, Inc. , Retired U.S. Air Force Veteran Dr. Maryam Khazraee, Founder, Rx Pharmacist, LLC, U.S. Army Veteran &#38; Lt. U.S. Public Health Service Matt Standish, Author, VA Outreach Specialist, U.S. Air Force Veteran Moderator: Carlos Gutierrez, U.S. Marine Corps Veteran; Innovation Outreach Specialist &#38;#8212; National Programs, Office of Innovation Outreach, USPTO 2:40 &#38;#8212; 2:45 p. m. Closing Explore the resources and tools available from the USPTO and learn about upcoming USPTO events. Carlos Gutierrez, U.S. Marine Corps Veteran; Innovation Outreach Specialist &#38;#8212; National Programs, Office of Innovation Outreach, USPTO</description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Getting started with Patent Public Search</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/learning-and-resources/researchers-librarians/getting-started-patent-public-search-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/learning-and-resources/researchers-librarians/getting-started-patent-public-search-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you puzzled by patent searching or confused by the patent searching options available on the internet? Whether you are a novice searcher or an experienced one, the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) is here to help. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-0</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-0</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in... Biology, Biomedical Engineering, Chemistry, Chemical Engineering, Computer Engineering, Computer Science, Design, Electrical Engineering, Mechanical Engineering, Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on January 10, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A fireside chat with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-0</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-0</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Come join us for a laid back and informational fireside chat that will give you an inside look at being a patent examiner at the USPTO. You will get the opportunity to engage in insightful conversations and get answers to your questions directly from team members. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part II: Drafting provisional patent applications</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-ii-drafting-provisional-patent-applications-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-ii-drafting-provisional-patent-applications-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>In part two of this eight-part recurring series, United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) experts discuss key differences between provisional and nonprovisional patent applications, filing requirements and fees, the different ways to file a provisional application, and more. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-1</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-1</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on January 24, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part III: Patent searching</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-iii-patent-searching-6</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-iii-patent-searching-6</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you interested in learning more about patent searching? In part three of this eight-part recurring series, United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) experts will discuss preliminary searching using the suggested seven-step strategy and more. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-2</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-2</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on January 31, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-1</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-1</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on February 6 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-3</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-3</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on February 14, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part V: Understanding the role of claims in a patent application</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-v-understanding-role-claims-patent-application-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-v-understanding-role-claims-patent-application-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you an inventor preparing to file a patent application? In part five of this eight-part recurring series, United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) experts will discuss the parts of the claim, show examples of claim illustrations from issued U.S. patents, and help participants develop a better appreciation of how a patent examiner views a claim. To get the most out of this workshop, you should have an intermediate knowledge of the intellectual property (IP) system and of patents, specifically. We recommend that you complete the previous sessions in the series, Part I: IP basics and Part IV: Learn how to draft your patent application, before attending. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on February 21, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VI: Learn how to protect your IP abroad</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vi-learn-how-protect-your-ip-abroad-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vi-learn-how-protect-your-ip-abroad-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Did you know that patents offer territorial rights, which means there is no such thing as an international or global patent? Learn how to help protect your intellectual property (IP) in foreign jurisdictions. In part six of this eight-part recurring series, United States Patent and Trademark Office's (USPTO) International Patent Legal Administration experts will discuss considerations and options for filing foreign patent applications. The discussion will include an overview of the Patent Cooperation Treaty (PCT) and the use of the Paris Convention for non-PCT countries. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on February 28, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VII: How to file a patent application using Patent Center</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vii-how-file-patent-application-using-patent-center-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vii-how-file-patent-application-using-patent-center-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Looking for more information on using Patent Center? In part seven of this eight-part recurring series, United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) experts will teach participants how to use this tool to file and manage patent documents online. This presentation will feature filing application documents in DOCX format, including using Patent Center training mode to practice filing. You will learn about some helpful resources, such as the Inventors Assistance Center (IAC) and the Patent Electronics Business Center (EBC). Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-6</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-6</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on March 6, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VIII: Common mistakes and post-filing support</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-viii-common-mistakes-and-post-filing-support-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-viii-common-mistakes-and-post-filing-support-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you an inventor? Join us for this session full of important tips on filing a patent application and what to do after you file for a patent. In the final part of this eight-part recurring series, you will learn about common mistakes to avoid, and you'll gain a better understanding of post-filing procedures and support. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-7</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-7</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on March 13, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-8</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-8</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on March 20, at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-2</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-2</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on March 28 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A fireside chat with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-1</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-1</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Come join us for a laid back and informational fireside chat that will give you an inside look at being a patent examiner at the USPTO. You will get the opportunity to engage in insightful conversations and get answers to your questions directly from team members. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-3</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-3</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on May 15 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A fireside chat with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-2</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-2</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Come join us for a laid back and informational fireside chat that will give you an inside look at being a patent examiner at the USPTO. You will get the opportunity to engage in insightful conversations and get answers to your questions directly from team members. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on July 9 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner. </description>
</item>

 
</channel>
</rss>