<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
 <title>USPTO Other Events</title>
<link>https://guides.lib.ucr.edu/c.php?g=932732</link>
 <description>This feed provides easy access to USPTO Other events.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
 <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 09:57:10 PST</lastBuildDate>
<webManager>katherine.koziar@ucr.edu</webManager>

 
<item> <title>Kickstart your federal career: Navigating USAJOBS and the federal resume</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/kickstart-your-federal-career-navigating-usajobs-and-federal-resume</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/kickstart-your-federal-career-navigating-usajobs-and-federal-resume</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a career in public service, but you're not sure where to start? Join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) on Tuesday, April 30, 2-3 p. m. ET, for an informational webinar to gain insights on understanding the USAJOBS platform and how to put your best foot forward in your application.  By attending this event, you'll hear from one of our Office of Human Resources team members and learn: How to navigate USAJOBSHow to read a job announcement What to (and what not to) include in your federal resume Tips and tricks for creating your federal resume Join session You do not need to register for this event. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. Browse current vacancies at USPTO via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Exploring invention and intellectual property with Rory Cooper's adaptive technology lesson plan</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/exploring-invention-and-intellectual-property-rory-coopers-adaptive-technology</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/exploring-invention-and-intellectual-property-rory-coopers-adaptive-technology</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 18:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>For this month's K-12 education webinar, join the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) and STEMis ED in a professional development session for educators on Tuesday, April 30, from 6-7 p. m. ET. This engaging ed Webinar will demonstrate how educators can use the Rory Cooper lesson plan to encourage innovation and problem-solving in their students. This dynamic, free lesson plan&#8212;aligned with the Rory Cooper USPTO Inventor Trading Card&#8212;uses low-cost materials to incorporate hands-on activities that offer a multifaceted, interdisciplinary approach to learning. It is designed to inspire students to delve into the world of adaptive technology and disability awareness. Visit the event page to learn more and and sign up. You can also visit Ed Web's Tips and Tricks page to learn more about how to view the live presentation and access the recording, earn your CE certificate, and use Ed Web's new accessibility features. Register today This webinar will be presented by: Doug Scott is an engineering and design teacher based in Massachusetts with many years of experience incorporating IP, invention, and innovation into his curriculums. He is a featured invention educator in a USPTO Journeys of Innovation story and was awarded the Presidential Award for Excellence in Math and Science Teaching. Doug has led students in his classes to acquire multiple patents, including one for a 'Multi-component robot for below ice search and rescue. ' Joyce Ward is the Director of the Students and Learners Division in the USPTO's Office of Public Engagement, which focuses on expanding outreach to K-12 educators and students, and integrating IP concepts, invention, innovation, and entrepreneurship into learning environments across the country. Joyce has led initiatives like the USPTO Science of Innovation series, the National Summer Teacher Institute on Innovation, STEM, and Intellectual Property (NSTI), the Master Teacher of Invention and Intellectual Property (MTIP) program, the Girl Scouts intellectual property patch, and the USPTO Inventor Trading Card series. USPTO professional development webinars The USPTO hosts monthly professional development webinars for K-12 educators interested in integrating IP, innovation, and invention activities into their STEM/STEAM curriculum. Whether you're a school administrator, teacher, student, parent, or caregiver, you are welcome to join us every month to hear from educators and learn about different types of IP, including patents, trademarks, copyrights, and trade secrets. These sessions can help inspire a classroom of problem solvers and shape career choices. Webinars are held once a month. Visit the USPTO's Kids, students, and educators page to learn more. For questions about the event, email education@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Invention-Con San Jose</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/invention-con-san-jose</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/invention-con-san-jose</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:45:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>World Intellectual Property Day 2024-Capitol Hill</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/world-intellectual-property-day-2024-capitol-hill</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/world-intellectual-property-day-2024-capitol-hill</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-12</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-12</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on May 1 at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-13</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-13</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on May 8 at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Attend the 17th annual Design Day</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/attend-17th-annual-design-day</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/attend-17th-annual-design-day</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 10:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Join us virtually or in person for a lively and thought-provoking discussion about the various aspects of design patents on Thursday, May 9, from 10 a. m. to 5 p. m. ET at United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) headquarters in Alexandria, Virginia. Get insights from USPTO design managers, design patent practitioners, and industrial designers. Design Day is co-sponsored by American Intellectual Property Law Association (AIPLA), the Intellectual Property Owners Association (IPO), and the USPTO. No CLE credit is offered for attendance. Register to attend in-person    Register to attend virtually For more information, please email DesignDay@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part V: Understanding the role of claims in a patent application</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-v-understanding-role-claims-patent-application-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-v-understanding-role-claims-patent-application-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you an inventor preparing to file a patent application? In part five of this eight-part recurring series, our experts will discuss the parts of the claim, show examples of claim illustrations from issued U.S. patents, and help participants develop a better appreciation of how a patent examiner views a claim. To get the most out of this workshop, you should have an intermediate knowledge of the intellectual property (IP) system and of patents specifically. We recommend that you complete the previous sessions in the series, Part I: IP basics and Part IV: Learn how to draft your patent application, before attending. Register today For more information, please email RockyMountain@uspto.gov or SiliconValley@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Exploring your options: USPTO resources and Small Business Innovation Research or Small Business Technology Transfer programs</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/uspto-resources-and-sbir-sttr</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/uspto-resources-and-sbir-sttr</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Public webinar on recent Guidance on Use of Artificial Intelligence-Based Tools in Practice Before the USPTO</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/guidance-use-artificial-intelligence-based-tools-practice-uspto</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/guidance-use-artificial-intelligence-based-tools-practice-uspto</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>The USPTO announced Guidance on Use of Artificial Intelligence-Based Tools in Practice Before the United States Patent and Trademark Office in the Federal Register on April 11, 2024. This guidance reminds individuals involved in proceedings before the USPTO of the pertinent rules and policies, helps inform those same individuals of the risks associated with the use of AI systems, and provides suggestions to mitigate those risks.  In order to provide you the opportunity to have your questions about the guidance answered by our experts, we are hosting a webinar on Wednesday, May 15, from 1-2 p. m. ET. USPTO personnel will provide an overview of the guidance and answer your questions relating to the guidance. Questions pursuant to the guidance MUST be submitted in advance to aipartnership@uspto.gov by May 12, 2024. While we will attempt to respond to as many questions as possible, time constraints may prevent us from answering all questions. The event is free and open to the public. Register today Agenda Topic Welcome and opening remarks Overview of the published guidance Panel Q&#38;AQuestions regarding the event can be submitted to aipartnership@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-3</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-3</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on May 15 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Regional innovation roundtable: IP, manufacturing, and export markets-a discussion with the USPTO's IP attach&#38;#233;s</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/regional-innovation-roundtable-ip-manufacturing-and-export-markets-discussion</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/regional-innovation-roundtable-ip-manufacturing-and-export-markets-discussion</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 09:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VI: Learn how to protect your IP abroad</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vi-learn-how-protect-your-ip-abroad-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vi-learn-how-protect-your-ip-abroad-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Did you know that patents offer territorial rights, meaning that there is no such thing as an international or global patent? Learn how to help protect your intellectual property (IP) in foreign jurisdictions. In part six of this eight-part recurring series, International Patent Legal Administration experts will discuss considerations and options for filing foreign patent applications. The discussion will include an overview of the Patent Cooperation Treaty (PCT) and the use of the Paris Convention for non-PCT countries. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-14</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-14</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on May 22 at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Dialogue on intellectual property and space commercialization</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/dialogue-intellectual-property-and-space-commercialization</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/dialogue-intellectual-property-and-space-commercialization</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 09:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description> </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-15</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-15</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on May 29 at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-16</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-16</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on June 5 at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VII: How to file a patent application using Patent Center</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vii-how-file-patent-application-using-patent-center-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-vii-how-file-patent-application-using-patent-center-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Looking for more information on using Patent Center? In part seven of this eight-part recurring series, our experts will teach participants how to use this tool to file and manage patent documents online. This presentation will feature filing application documents in DOCX format, including using Patent Center training mode to practice filing. You will learn about some helpful resources, such as the Inventors Assistance Center (IAC) and the Patent Electronics Business Center (EBC). Register today For more information, please email RockyMountain@uspto.gov or SiliconValley@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-17</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-17</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on June 12 at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>The Path to a Patent, Part VIII: Common mistakes and post-filing support</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-viii-common-mistakes-and-post-filing-support-5</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/about-us/events/path-patent-part-viii-common-mistakes-and-post-filing-support-5</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 14:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Are you an inventor? Join us for this session full of important tips on filing a patent application and what to do after you file for a patent. In the final part of this eight-part recurring series, you will learn about common mistakes to avoid, and you'll gain a better understanding of post-filing procedures and support. Register today For more information, please email SiliconValley@uspto.gov or RockyMountain@uspto.gov. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A fireside chat with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-2</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/fireside-chat-uspto-patent-examiners-2</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Come join us for a laid back and informational fireside chat that will give you an inside look at being a patent examiner at the USPTO. You will get the opportunity to engage in insightful conversations and get answers to your questions directly from team members. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>Virtual office hour with USPTO patent examiners</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-18</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/virtual-office-hour-uspto-patent-examiners-18</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Calling all scientists and engineers! Seeking a career at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner? If you are a U.S. citizen and are graduating this year with a focus in...Biology Biomedical Engineering Chemistry Chemical Engineering Computer Engineering Computer Science Design Electrical Engineering Mechanical Engineering Physics ...then bring your questions about the agency, the role, and the hiring process to this informal Q&#38;A session with current USPTO patent examiners on June 26 at noon ET. Our team members are excited to answer your questions, chat with you, and provide you with more information about this opportunity. Join session You do not need to register for this event but come prepared with any questions you may have. We hope to see you there! For more information, contact recruitment@uspto.gov. When you are ready to apply, submit your application via USAJOBS. </description>
</item>

 
<item> <title>A day in the life of a USPTO patent examiner</title>
	<link>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-4</link>
	<guid>https://www.uspto.gov/jobs/day-life-uspto-patent-examiner-4</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 12:00:00 EST</pubDate>
	<description>Do you want a challenging career? Would you like the opportunity to work from home nationwide with a flexible schedule? Do you want to be a part of a culture of inclusivity and camaraderie, and a community that leads America toward breakthroughs in innovation? Are you a U.S. citizen graduating this year with a focus in any of these fields?	Biology	Biomedical Engineering	Chemistry	Chemical Engineering	Computer Engineering	Computer Science	Design	Electrical Engineering	Mechanical Engineering	Physics 	If you answered yes to any of these questions, you may belong at the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as a patent examiner! We recruit the most promising at America's Innovation Agency, and we encourage you to take the step forward in your journey today by joining us on July 9 at noon ET for an informational webinar on becoming a patent examiner. </description>
</item>

 
</channel>
</rss>